The 25th anniversary of the first public performance of Phantom of the Opera.
The Phantom of the Opera at the Royal Albert Hall is a music,
drama, romance film directed by Laurence Connor.
A disfigured musical genius, hidden away in the Paris Opera House, terrorises the opera
company for the unwitting benefit of a young protégée whom he trains and loves.
The 25th anniversary of the first public performance of Phantom of the Opera was
celebrated with a grand performance at the Royal Albert Hall in London.
The Phantom, played by Ramin Karimloo.
Christine Daae, played by Sierra Boggess.
Raoul, Vicomte de Chagny, played by Hadley Fraser.
Madame Giry, played by Liz Robertson.
Joseph Buquet, played by Nick Holder.
Carlotta Giudicelli, played by Wendy Ferguson.
The Phantom of the Opera at the Royal Albert Hall is a 2011 British concert film adaptation of the 1986 stage
musical The Phantom of the Opera by Andrew Lloyd Webber, itself based on the 1910 novel by Gaston Leroux.
To celebrate the 25th anniversary of the musical, three special performances on Saturday 1 October 2011 at 7.30pm and Sunday 2 October 2011
at 1.30pm and 7.00pm were filmed at the Royal Albert Hall, the third of which was screened live worldwide on 2 October 2011.
For further releases, footage from all three performances was edited together.
The film explores themes of opera, london, england,
paris, france, love triangle, musical.
The tone is emotional.